<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: work | burnedpixel]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.burnedpixel.com/blog/categories/work/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.burnedpixel.com/"/>
  <updated>2014-08-30T18:20:51-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.burnedpixel.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Chris Chernoff]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Call of Duty: ELITE]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.burnedpixel.com/work/call-of-duty-elite"/>
    <updated>2013-01-10T00:00:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.burnedpixel.com/work/call-of-duty-elite</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Call of Duty has become the highest grossing entertainment franchise of all time. Toppling other games like Halo and feature films like Avatar and The Dark Knight, Call of Duty’s annual release cycle and user base of nearly 30 million have allowed it to amass an unparalleled following in the game industry.</p>

<!--more-->

<hr />

<h4 id="background">Background</h4>

<p>In 2010 Call of Duty’s publisher Activision started the Call of Duty: Elite project with the goal of allowing users to engage with the game’s vast arrays of data, participate in competitions, and ultimately foster an online community for their mega-series.</p>

<p>As one of the central UX designers on the project, I was tasked with creating an online service that would have to accommodate and balance a formidable set of challenges: mountains of data, engaging our sophisticated and diverse user base, and massive scale.</p>

<p><a href="/uploads/work/call-of-duty-elite/boxes.jpg"><img src="/uploads/work/call-of-duty-elite/boxes.jpg"></a></p>

<hr />

<h4 id="user-research">User Research</h4>

<p>There is a wide range of players with different skill levels, play styles, and social objectives in Call of Duty. An important part of the research phase for this project was establishing what motivated players to keep coming back for more, and what factors were most important to these different segments of players. Striking the balance between maintaining the interest of the hardcore and appealing to newcomers was critical.</p>

<p>Call of Duty is not an easy game to pick up and learn. To help users acclimate themselves, the foundation of multiplayer gameplay revolves around specific tangible goals such as, “Get 10 kills with this gun, and you’ll level up.” </p>

<p>This completionist focus can carry many users through weeks or even months of play time. However, leveling up and unlocking rewards only takes players so far.</p>

<p><a href="/uploads/work/call-of-duty-elite/why.jpg"><img src="/uploads/work/call-of-duty-elite/why.jpg"></a></p>

<p>Players reach a crossroads where their playtime starts tailing off, or they begin creating their own sets of challenges and goals to keep the game interesting and rewarding for them. It’s at this point where you can differentiate between traditional completionist gamers, and players who thirst for more.</p>

<p>This second group of players is higher in skill, plays for more extended periods of time, and contains some of Call of Duty’s most die-hard fans. However, eventually they too reach a skill or satisfaction plateau and once again begin to grow tired of the game. </p>

<p>Once players reach a certain level of individual mastery, they often do one of two things: form or join a group to achieve a collective success and help improve other players, or try to get widespread recognition for their skills and accomplishments via social media to satisfy. Both of these behaviors strive for a concept we called “group mastery.”</p>

<p>Essentially once players lose interest in the way the game is teaching <em>them</em> how to play, they decide to improve by teaching directly (in groups) and/or indirectly (YouTube videos, strategy websites, etc).</p>

<p><a href="/uploads/work/call-of-duty-elite/meaningful.jpg"><img src="/uploads/work/call-of-duty-elite/meaningful.jpg"></a></p>

<hr />

<h4 id="engaging-and-challenging-a-competitive-user-base">Engaging and challenging a competitive user base</h4>

<p>I worked with the rest of the design team to build Elite around satisfying these user needs. At the heart of the service is a set of statistics and analysis called the Player Card. Here players can get information on their performance trends, as well as research their strengths and weaknesses. </p>

<p>This is a “ground floor” of the service that users of all skill levels use. There is also an almost encyclopedic section of the site that helps them understand terminology and learn to play with weapons, explore new maps modes, and other gameplay features.</p>

<p><a href="/uploads/work/call-of-duty-elite/career_summary.jpg"><img class="left" src="/uploads/work/call-of-duty-elite/career_summary.jpg" width="200" height="200"></a>
<a href="/uploads/work/call-of-duty-elite/recent_matches.jpg"><img class="center" src="/uploads/work/call-of-duty-elite/recent_matches.jpg" width="200" height="200"></a></p>

<p>To challenge players, I created a system of Elite-exclusive competitions that gave them a chance to win digital and tangible prizes. Players in the “individual mastery” phase of their Call of Duty careers were particularly intrigued by these competitions, as it allowed them to hone in on objectives that other skilled players were gunning for. </p>

<p>Up until this feature’s introduction, all skill metrics shown in Call of Duty were inclusive of the entire population and without the context of a specific objective.</p>

<p>It was quite exciting to flip the switch and see millions of players across the world fight for iPads, Call of Duty branded skateboard decks and backpacks, and even Jeeps! In addition to real prizes, each competition would award digital badges to its successful participants. </p>

<p>The spoils of these competitions, particularly the digital badges awarded to participants who finished in the upper percentiles, became coveted items in the community and left players yearning for more ways to compete.</p>

<p><a href="/uploads/work/call-of-duty-elite/competitions.jpg"><img src="/uploads/work/call-of-duty-elite/competitions.jpg"></a></p>

<hr />

<h4 id="clans-encouraging-player-organization-and-collaboration">Clans: Encouraging player organization and collaboration</h4>

<p>For decades gamers have teamed up into what are known as “clans” to not only play better in their games of choice, but for the camaraderie and friendships that spawn from them. Clans across the world create their own websites, set up chatrooms and times to play, and run their own tournaments and recruiting drives.</p>

<p><a href="/uploads/work/call-of-duty-elite/clan_hq.jpg"><img src="/uploads/work/call-of-duty-elite/clan_hq.jpg"></a></p>

<p>It only made sense to bolster this strong pre-existing concept by supporting it in Call of Duty Elite. Clans were the key to Elite encouraging the player engagement concept I mentioned earlier, group mastery.</p>

<p>As lead designer on clans, I designed a wide range of features that complemented in-game functionality and added meaningful group-based objectives that individual clan members could work towards for the greater good of their clan. </p>

<p>I wanted to alleviate the organizational and social burden clans had of setting up their own websites, and encourage them to use Elite as their online headquarters. On their “Clan HQ”, Clan members could communicate among themselves and other players in the community to work on game strategy and build tight relationships and intense rivalries.</p>

<p><a href="/uploads/work/call-of-duty-elite/clan_landing.jpg"><img src="/uploads/work/call-of-duty-elite/clan_landing.jpg"></a></p>

<p>Some clans start as groups of personal friends, but many form organically from chance meetings in-game. However, with tens of millions of users Call of Duty multiplayer can be a large and intimidating place. </p>

<p>Knowing this, I developed a few features that made it easier to find clans for users with fewer friends or contacts in the Call of Duty community. Users could peruse clans that friends and acquaintances were in, as well as relevant clans in the community with similar interests and skill levels. </p>

<p>Additionally, players seeking clans and clans seeking players could head over to clan recruitment forums and match up.</p>

<p>Once established on Elite, clans could participate in clan-specific competitions that would not only reward each member with items to use in game, but reward the clan itself and encourage teamwork.</p>

<p><a href="/uploads/work/call-of-duty-elite/clan_challenges.jpg"><img src="/uploads/work/call-of-duty-elite/clan_challenges.jpg"></a></p>

<hr />

<h4 id="conclusion">Conclusion</h4>

<p>The ultimate goal of Call of Duty Elite is to improve and expand each player’s gaming experience throughout the Call of Duty series. </p>

<p>Elite achieves this by providing rich data, meaningful competitions and goals, and most importantly by encouraging and simplifying the process for gamers to play together. </p>

<p>With over 12 million registered users and two million clans to date and hundreds of thousands of players participating in competitions every day, Elite has written the book on what a game franchise needs to do in order to take user engagement to the next level.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Logicbuy]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.burnedpixel.com/work/logicbuy"/>
    <updated>2013-01-09T00:00:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.burnedpixel.com/work/logicbuy</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>LogicBUY is a deals and coupons community that prides itself on saving users as much money as possible. I was hired to take part in a revamp of their website to bolster user engagement, improve the quality and consistency of their listings, and to simplify the process for users to save money while shopping.</p>

<!--more-->

<hr />

<h4 id="background">Background</h4>

<p>LogicBUY had accumulated a substantial amount of content, however it was struggling to keep users engaged and convert new users into returning users.</p>

<p>It became clear that LogicBUY’s most successful competitors were those that used a careful blend of legibility, brevity, and speed. While some sites displayed more information for deals and coupons than others, generally speaking the ones that allowed users to more quickly and efficiently digest their content were the most successful.</p>

<p><a href="/uploads/work/logicbuy/competitors.jpg"><img class="center" src="/uploads/work/logicbuy/competitors.jpg"></a></p>

<hr />

<h4 id="user-research">User Research</h4>

<p>LogicBUY’s user base is diverse across levels of engagement, but generally the dividing characteristic is: passive or active. </p>

<p>Passive users visit LogicBUY either because they are shopping on a specific site and want to find discounts for it, or they’re just browsing for good deals in general.</p>

<p>In addition to casually browsing, active users contribute to LogicBUY by submitting deal and coupons to their inventory. In exchange, these users get satisfaction that they’ve saved other folks money through ratings, comments, and votes.</p>

<p>It became clear that a successful strategy for LogicBUY would have to balance these user groups by presenting data consistently and efficiently, while displaying credit and appreciation where it’s due.</p>

<hr />

<h4 id="speed-is-of-the-essence">Speed is of the essence</h4>

<p>I could spend all day looking for deals, but most people aren’t like that.</p>

<p>Instead, I wanted to make it easy for people to find what they were looking for as quickly as possible. The navigation system for the site quickly indicated to users the primary categories they could expect to find deals and coupons for on LogicBUY. </p>

<p>A prominent search tool also allowed users to quickly hone in on a specific item or store.</p>

<p>The heart of this website are the thousands of deal and coupon listings. In past iterations of the site, this information was muddled and not easy to browse through. Therefore, special thought was given to the deal “unit” this information was organized into. At a glance, each listing had to be interesting and informative, but not be overly congested with unnecessary content.</p>

<hr />

<h4 id="multiple-viewing-modes-to-cater-to-user-needs">Multiple viewing modes to cater to user needs</h4>

<p><a href="/uploads/work/logicbuy/grid_items.jpg"><img class="center" src="/uploads/work/logicbuy/grid_items.jpg"></a></p>

<p>A new grid view provided a visually oriented way to browse deals on the site. Users who preferred to “window shop” could do so quickly by consuming a large number of deal photos.</p>

<p>Upon hover, a deal in the grid could be expanded to reveal secondary deal details. </p>

<p>For users who preferred a more systematic and data-driven browsing method, the list view provided entries that were streamlined to provide maximum scanabilty at first glance. </p>

<p>If users were intrigued by a deal, they were be able to expand it to discover additional details quickly without having to change pages.</p>

<p><a href="/uploads/work/logicbuy/list_items.jpg"><img class="center" src="/uploads/work/logicbuy/list_items.jpg"></a></p>

<hr />

<h4 id="allow-users-to-quickly-and-easily-contribute">Allow users to quickly and easily contribute</h4>

<p>There are a lot of key pieces of information that go into a good deal, and it was important that the listings on LogicBUY maintained a consistent presentation of this data.</p>

<p>To streamline this process for users, I introduced a two-step process that would automatically retrieve most of the important data for users.</p>

<p><a href="/uploads/work/logicbuy/deal_submit.jpg"><img class="center" src="/uploads/work/logicbuy/deal_submit.jpg"></a></p>

<p>Step one is as simple as pasting the URL to the deal you found. LogicBUY would instantaneously visit this URL, grab the pertinent information, and have it ready for you to review in step two. </p>

<p>After a quick once over and minor adjustments, your deal was ready for the public and could begin saving people money!</p>

<hr />

<h4 id="community-content-curation">Community content curation</h4>

<p>Due to the fact that a “good” deal is often relative, another key area of the site that was addressed was how users affected content on the site. </p>

<p>By introducing voting, commenting, and tagging tools, LogicBUY’s dedicated community could self-curate many of the deals and coupons that would come about during each day.</p>

<p><a href="/uploads/work/logicbuy/comments.jpg"><img class="center" src="/uploads/work/logicbuy/comments.jpg"></a></p>

<hr />

<h4 id="conclusion">Conclusion</h4>

<p><a href="/uploads/work/logicbuy/deal_homepage.jpg"><img class="center" src="/uploads/work/logicbuy/deal_homepage.jpg"></a></p>

<p>My involvement with LogicBUY continued through three phases of feature sets and deployment. As a result of the hard work put into this project, LogicBUY has seen a significant statistical increase in nearly every measurable analytics category. </p>

<p>Their daily unique visitors tripled and time on site more than doubled. Most importantly, user registration and user submissions increased dramatically due to the more streamlined processes. LogicBUY also received numerous accolades in the deal community for their improved experience, ultimately beating out industry mainstays such as DealNews, SlickDeals, and FatWallet.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Mitsubishi]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.burnedpixel.com/work/mitsubishi"/>
    <updated>2013-01-08T00:00:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.burnedpixel.com/work/mitsubishi</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Mitsubishi build reliable well performing cars and SUVs, but in recent years have struggled to retain a healthy portion of the US auto market.</p>

<p>The goal was to educate potential car buyers on Mitsubishi’s product lineup and allow them to outfit a vehicle that was both practical and affordable.</p>

<!--more-->

<hr />

<h4 id="background">Background</h4>

<p>Mitsubishi’s most popular vehicle of the past decade has without a doubt been their Lancer line. Offering a fantastic value for its price, it had carved out a niche among value minded buyers who enjoyed spirited driving. </p>

<p>The high performance Evolution (Evo) model of the line acted as a halo car of sorts, as it was often featured prominently in racing series and was a favorite among younger demographics.</p>

<p>However, as climate changed in the auto industry and many consumers began purchasing SUV/Crossover hybrids, Mitsubishi found itself without a horse in the race.</p>

<p>They introduced a new model to compete in this space, the Outlander, and wanted to have a revamped online presence to coincide with its introduction.</p>

<hr />

<h4 id="user-research">User Research</h4>

<p>I conducted user interviews to get a handle on what some of the problems with the existing Mitsubishi site were. In addition to my own observations and competitive research, a few common friction points emerged.</p>

<p><a href="/uploads/work/mitsubishi/testing.jpg"><img class="center" src="/uploads/work/mitsubishi/testing.jpg"></a></p>

<p>The first problem most prospective car buyers encountered was that they simply didn’t know much about the product lineup or what type of vehicle suits them best.</p>

<p>Arrays of technical features and jargon further clouded their discovery and decision-making processes.</p>

<p>Even when users were able to identify a suitable vehicle for themselves, nebulous financial terms and details perpetuated the mistrust that users hold of auto manufacturers.</p>

<hr />

<h4 id="beginning-a-relationship-with-straightforward-presentation">Beginning a relationship with straightforward presentation</h4>

<p>As a first step towards users potentially choosing a Mitsubishi as their next vehicle, the vehicle detail pages were revamped to convey the context and strengths of each vehicle. </p>

<p><a href="/uploads/work/mitsubishi/car_detail.jpg"><img class="center" src="/uploads/work/mitsubishi/car_detail.jpg"></a></p>

<p>The auto industry tends to use complicated terminology “Double Wishbone Suspension” that confuses and alienates potential customers.</p>

<p>With Mitsubishi, we wanted to ensure that vehicle features were clearly highlighted and explained.</p>

<p>[<img class="left" src="/uploads/work/mitsubishi/safety<em>1.jpg" width="200" height="200">](/uploads/work/mitsubishi/safety</em>1.jpg)</p>

<p>[<img class="center" src="/uploads/work/mitsubishi/safety<em>2.jpg" width="200" height="200">](/uploads/work/mitsubishi/safety</em>2.jpg)</p>

<hr />

<h4 id="building-a-practical-vehicle-in-your-budget">Building a practical vehicle in your budget</h4>

<p>A staple of all car manufacturer websites is a build and price tool. By being able to appoint a vehicle with only the features they need, users are able to construct a clear idea of how purchasing or leasing will cost them on a monthly basis.</p>

<p>The build and price tool needed one thing: transparency. By pigeonholing key information about the cars, the current tool lacked any sense of honesty or completion.</p>

<p>The revamped build tool allowed users to filter the vehicle lineup by a variety of parameters. If they still had difficulty deciding on a model, colors, options, and other details, the site helped them pose questions to their friends via social media on what car or color to choose.</p>

<p>I added a receipt system to keep track of what features and options were being added to the car, and how much each item cost. Additionally, I added a progress tracker to indicate how far along in the building process a user was. </p>

<p>[<img src="/uploads/work/mitsubishi/build<em>2.jpg">](/uploads/work/mitsubishi/build</em>2.jpg)</p>

<p>I studied the visual language of e-commerce checkout processes and decided that by adding a step-by-step tracker at the top, users would gain a sense of accomplishment for completing the build process.
A continuously updating estimated monthly payment module was another feature that added a critical point of reference. Unless they were paying in cash, nearly all users wanted to know what a car will cost monthly.</p>

<p>Finally, I allowed users to click on any feature, option, or package throughout the process so they could easily discover why they might want or not want a particular option. </p>

<p>Many users have a basic knowledge cars and their underlying technologies. However testing showed that when presented with a list of options to choose from, users who knew less about cars gave up because they did not know what certain things were. </p>

<p>By including descriptions of all the technology on the car, more users could confidently continue on.</p>

<p>[<img src="/uploads/work/mitsubishi/build<em>4.jpg">](/uploads/work/mitsubishi/build</em>4.jpg)</p>

<hr />

<h4 id="welcoming-owners-into-the-fold">Welcoming owners into the fold</h4>

<p>Another area of the Mitsubishi site that we wanted to improve was the owners section. While car companies insist on “welcoming you into the family” right as you’re about to sign on the dotted line, you rarely feel the love after you’ve been thrown the keys. </p>

<p>Whether you’re just trying to find out where your oil cap is, or where to go for your next service, it was clear that Mitsubishi needed to beef up their owners section.</p>

<p><a href="/uploads/work/mitsubishi/owners.jpg"><img class="center" src="/uploads/work/mitsubishi/owners.jpg"></a></p>

<p>In addition to vehicle specific information, the owners section was also intended to help facilitate conversations and meetings between owners. </p>

<p>Every year millions of people sign on to car forums, go to auto expos, and head to the track. Mitsubishi should be the collecting point for many of these people who share the same interests. </p>

<p>By leveraging vehicle and location specific information, the site populated a calendar of events to suit each owners needs, and remind them of when they are on their mobile phone.</p>

<hr />

<h4 id="conclusion">Conclusion</h4>

<p>We walked the same test participants as the beginning of the project through the new interface. The general sentiments that carried throughout the sessions were that subjects felt less overwhelmed by confusing terminology and better informed to identify a vehicle for their needs.</p>

<p><a href="/uploads/work/mitsubishi/builder.jpg"><img class="center" src="/uploads/work/mitsubishi/builder.jpg"></a></p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Nexen]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.burnedpixel.com/work/nexen"/>
    <updated>2013-01-07T00:00:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.burnedpixel.com/work/nexen</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Nexen is the best tire company you’ve never heard of. They make great tires for a fraction of the cost of their American, European, and Japanese competitors, while maintaining comparable performance and reliability. </p>

<p>This project coincided with an aggressive marketing campaign to boost their stateside awareness and brand perception.</p>

<!--more-->

<hr />

<h4 id="background">Background</h4>

<p>Their existing online catalog was difficult to navigate and lacked clear-cut descriptions for their products.</p>

<p>Nexen needed to win over potential customers by making it easy for them to understand the strengths and intended applications of their different product lines.</p>

<p><a href="/uploads/work/nexen/competitors.jpg"><img class="center" src="/uploads/work/nexen/competitors.jpg"></a></p>

<hr />

<h4 id="context-for-tire-application">Context for tire application</h4>

<p>The first order of business was to organize different families of tires together and display them in settings that would easily convey their strengths.</p>

<p><a href="/uploads/work/nexen/winter_tires.jpg"><img class="center" src="/uploads/work/nexen/winter_tires.jpg"></a></p>

<hr />

<h4 id="simplified-comparison-metrics">Simplified comparison metrics</h4>

<p>While tires appear to be simple rings of rubber, there’s actually quite a bit of engineering that goes into them.  UTQG, Load Index and Speed Rating are just a few of the data parameters that tire companies use to objectively judge performance. </p>

<p>Where general consumers are concerned, this data in its raw form is rarely useful. It would have been foolish to simply discard all of these specs because naturally they provide a basis of comparison. </p>

<p>However, I knew that for Nexen to be able to effectively communicate to consumers, they needed something that explained what their products did in basic terms.</p>

<p><a href="/uploads/work/nexen/tire_detail.jpg"><img class="center" src="/uploads/work/nexen/tire_detail.jpg"></a></p>

<p>By adding creating benchmarks based on this data, all of the tires on Nexen’s site could quickly be analyzed and compared with each other. Users could assess a tire based on their priorities (e.g. Cost and Treadwear) and not have to bother themselves with abstract data.</p>

<p>Technology badges helped indicate what tasks each tire model did best. Whether it’s ride quality or grip level, Nexen puts just as much research into their tires as other manufacturers. To explain how certain technologies help a tire perform better under different conditions, video featurettes were added to help potential buyers make the most educated decisions.</p>

<hr />

<h4 id="conclusion">Conclusion</h4>

<p>All of these changes added up to a site that not only encouraged exploration, but informed potential tire shoppers in a clear and concise manner along the way.</p>

<p><a href="/uploads/work/nexen/homepage.jpg"><img class="center" src="/uploads/work/nexen/homepage.jpg"></a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
